Guide to the Dick Thornburgh Papers, 1932- AIS.1998.30.09
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Campaign for Governor of Pennsylvania, 1978; IX.
  - Chron Files and News Clippings, 11.
    The 1978 campaign chron files contain news clippings that follow the campaign virtually day by day. They date January, 1977-November 7, 1978, and are arranged chronologically by month and day.
    The chron files illuminate the progress of the campaign in great detail, and include for example: event schedules, political issues, debate materials, press releases, and news clippings. There also are brochures, invitations, speech drafts, correspondence, polls and memos throughout. There is a useful alphabetical index to scheduled events at the beginning of this section, listing all the persons and organizations with whom candidate Thornburgh met throughout the campaign. At the end of each month, there also is a folder containing personal schedules of both Ginny Thornburgh and Bill Scranton.
    The news clippings are in three sections: Primary Election, General Election, and Post-Election/Transition. These news clippings include those about other candidates as well as Thornburgh/Scranton on the campaign trail and derive from both urban and rural newspapers statewide. The post election clippings cover Republican Party activities, Gettysburg ceremonies honoring Mamie Eisenhower, and items relating to the future Thornburgh administration cabinet and inaugural preparations.
    - Chron Files
      - Index to Schedules, 1977-1978 (Box 103, Folder 1)
      - November 28, 1976 (Box 103, Folder 2)
      - January 24-March 20, 1977 (Box 103, Folder 3)
      - March 22, 1977, March 31, 1977 (Box 103, Folder 4)
      - April 11-26, 1977 (Box 103, Folder 5-8)
      - April 28-May 6, 1977 (Box 103, Folder 9)
      - May 9-27, 1977 (Box 103, Folder 10-15)
      - May 31-June 5, 1977 (Box 103, Folder 16)
      - June 6-27, 1977 (Box 103, Folder 17-20)
      - June 27-July 2, 1977 (Box 103, Folder 21)
      - July, 1977 (Box 103, Folder 22-25)
      - August 15-31, 1977 (Box 103, Folder 26-27)
      - September 1-24, 1977 (Box 104, Folder 1-3)
      - September 25-October 1, 1977 (Box 104, Folder 4)
      - October, 1977 (Box 104, Folder 5-12)
      - October 30- November 5, 1977 (Box 104, Folder 13)
      - November,1977 (Box 104, Folder 14-19)
      - November 27- December 3, 1977 (Box 104, Folder 20)
      - December, 1977 (Box 105, Folder 1-5)
      - January, 1978 (Box 105, Folder 6-15)
      - February, 1978 (Box 105, Folder 16-44)
      - March, 1978 (Box 106, Folder 1-29)
      - April 1-18, 1978 (Box 106, Folder 30-46)
      - April 19-30, 1978 (Box 107, Folder 1-11)
      - May, 1978 (Box 107, Folder 12-31)
      - June, 1978 (Box 107, Folder 32-56)
      - July, 1978 (Box 108, Folder 1-31)
      - August 5-21, 1978 (Box 108, Folder 32-43)
      - August 22-31, 1978 (Box 109, Folder 1-10)
      - September, 1978 (Box 109, Folder 11-39)
      - October, 1978 (Box 110, Folder 1-31)
      - November, 1978 (Box 110, Folder 32-39)
      - Ginny Thornburgh's Schedules, February-November, 1978 (Box 110, Folder 40-43)
      - Bill Scranton's Schedules, June-November, 1978 (Box 110, Folder 44)
    - News Clippings
      - Primary Election
        - March-December, 1977 (Box 111, Folder 1-9)
        - January-April, 1978 (Box 111, Folder 10-19)
        - May 1-16, 1978 (Box 112, Folder 1-2)
      - General Election
        - May 17-July, 1978 (Box 112, Folder 3-15)
        - August-October 19, 1978 (Box 113, Folder 1-14)
        - October 20-November 7, 1978 (Box 114, Folder 1-12)
      - Post-Election
        - November 8-24, 1978 (Box 114, Folder 13-20)
        - November 25-December, 1978 (Box 115, Folder 1-11)
        - January 1-16, 1979 (Box 116, Folder 1-8)
      - Ginny Thornburgh
        - March, 1978-November, 1978 (Box 116, Folder 9)
  - Transition and Inaugural, 12.
    This portion of the collection is comprised of files that cover the Governor-elect's transition period from the general election in November 1978 until the Inauguration in January 1979, the time for what Thornburgh called "administration-building tasks." The contents are organized into seven sections: Election Results; Post Election Mail; "The Transition"; Study Team Organization; Study Team Reports; Cabinet Nominations; and Inaugural.
    The election results are detailed and identify the varying regions and constituencies which voted for Thornburgh/Scranton, and evaluations of the results, many with Thornburgh annotations. Also are included field reports from campaign workers around the state. In the next section there is Post Election mail that includes letters and notes of congratulations, offers of help, and correspondence from persons seeking jobs in the new administration.
    "The Transition" identifies the specific period of time between the November victory of Governor elect Thornburgh and his subsequent Inauguration in January. This section contains binders of information prepared by the outgoing Shapp administration, plans and security issues, agendas, and lists of Thornburgh's transition team, led by Rick Stafford. The next group, Study Team Organization, has files related to the selection of and schedules for experts to come and evaluate departments and issues and prioritize concerns for the incoming administration. Their Study Team Reports follow.
    A key additional responsibility of the transition team was assistance with the challenging process of identifying potential cabinet members for the Thornburgh administration. There were many suggestions, recommendations and research made available for consideration by Governor-elect Thornburgh in this all-important task.
    The final section specifically relates to the Inaugural, the plans, celebrations and myriad of arrangements. Materials for example include: memos, schedules, invitations, events, Ginny Thornburgh's Inaugural file, a family inaugural scrapbook by Ann Thornburgh, and ephemera. Included, too, is a volume of photographs from the Inaugural and related events, published subsequently by the Republican Party. After the thrills and joys of the Inaugural, the new Governor was ready!
    - Election Results
      - Primary Election Results, 1978 (Box 117, Folder 1)
      - 1978 Republican State Committee of PA Post Primary Statistics by County (Box 117, Folder 2)
      - County Results-Primary 1978 (Box 117, Folder 3)
      - "Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, Department of State Bureau of Elections and Commissions, Primary Election '78 - Official Results" by Barton A. Fields, Secretary of Commonwealth, July 31, 1978 (Box 117, Folder 4)
      - General Election Results and Official Certificate of Election, 1978-1979 (Box 117, Folder 5)
      - Murray Dickman Post Election Results, November 22, 1978 (Box 117, Folder 6)
      - Post election field reports by Kit Donahue, et al, November-December, 1978 (Box 117, Folder 7)
      - Registered Pennsylvania Voters, 1978 (Box 117, Folder 8)
      - PA State Legislative and Senatorial campaigns, 1978 (Box 117, Folder 9)
      - U.S. Congressional Races, 1978 (Box 117, Folder 10)
      - Pre 1978 Election Results (annotated by Thornburgh and staff) (Box 117, Folder 11)
    - Post Election Mail
      - Primary
        - Memo regarding post election Mail Handling system, December 18, 1978 (Box 118, Folder 1)
        - Letters of congratulations to Thornburgh (including replies), May-July, 1978 (Box 118, Folder 2-5)
        - Letters of congratulations to Ginny Thornburgh (including replies), May, 1978 (Box 118, Folder 6)
        - Letters of congratulations to PA Legislature, June 8 -15, 1978 (Box 118, Folder 7)
        - Letters of congratulations including offers of help, May-June, 1978 (Box 118, Folder 8)
      - General
        - Mailgrams, November 8, 1978 (Box 118, Folder 9)
        - Name List of Congratulatory Correspondence, November, 1978 (Box 118, Folder 10)
        - Letters addressed to "Dick and Ginny", November, 1978 (Box 118, Folder 11-12)
        - Cards addressed to "Dick and Ginny", November, 1978 (Box 118, Folder 13)
        - Personal Congratulations, November, 1978 (Box 118, Folder 14)
        - Correspondences with special enclosures, November 8, 1978-January 4, 1979 (Box 118, Folder 15)
        - Congratulatory Telegrams, November 8, 1978 (Box 118, Folder 16)
        - Thank you letters to volunteers, November-December, 1978 (Box 118, Folder 17)
        - Correspondence, November-December, 1978 (Box 119, Folder 1-2)
        - Letters, mailgrams and telegrams, November-December, 1978 (Box 119, Folder 3)
        - Christmas cards and congratulations, November-December, 1978 (Box 119, Folder 4)
        - Federal Officeholders, Governors, and Presidents, November, 1978 (Box 119, Folder 5)
        - State Senators, November, 1978 (Box 119, Folder 6)
        - State Representatives, November, 1978 (Box 119, Folder 7)
        - Judges, November, 1978 (Box 119, Folder 8)
        - Municipal and County Officials, November, 1978 (Box 119, Folder 9)
        - Newspaper editors and media persons, November, 1978 (Box 119, Folder 10)
        - State Committee, November, 1978 (Box 119, Folder 11)
        - County Chairman and Committees, November, 1978 (Box 119, Folder 12)
        - Local Committees, November, 1978 (Box 119, Folder 13)
        - GOP and Thornburgh Organizations (African American, Women, Youth), November, 1978 (Box 119, Folder 14)
        - Congratulations with Enclosed Contributions, October-December, 1978 (Box 119, Folder 15)
        - Names for Study Teams and Transition, November-December, 1978 (Box 119, Folder 16)
        - General Offers of Help, November-December, 1978 (Box 119, Folder 17-18)
        - Correspondence from State Officials and Secretaries, November 10-December 1, 1978 (Box 119, Folder 19)
        - Constituent letters of congratulations with subject concerns, November, 1977-December, 1978 (Box 119, Folder 20)
        - Letters Thornburgh sent to supporters (name and address lists included), November, 1978 (Box 120, Folder 1)
        - Letters to union members thanking them for notes of congratulations, November-December, 1978 (Box 120, Folder 2)
        - Chamber of Commerce, December 6, 1978 (Box 120, Folder 3)
        - Organizations, November-December, 1978 (Box 120, Folder 4)
        - Special Interest Groups, November-December, 1978 (Box 120, Folder 5)
        - Correspondences to Ginny, October-December, 1978 (Box 120, Folder 6)
    - The Transition
      - Copies of Mail Sent to Transition Team regarding issues and offers of help, November, 1978-January, 1979 (Box 120, Folder 7)
      - Governor Shapp transition binder, Government Operations, November, 1978 (Box 120, Folder 8)
      - Governor Shapp transition binder, "Government Operations," prepared for Governor-elect Thornburgh, November, 1978 (Box 120, Folder 9)
      - Plans and Memos, December 27, 1978 (Box 120, Folder 10)
      - New York Times Economic Magazine advertisement by the Pennsylvania Department of Commerce, December 7, 1978 (Box 120, Folder 11)
      - Security Information, undated (Box 120, Folder 12)
      - Transition Team Members, November 30, 1978-January 1, 1979 (Box 120, Folder 13)
      - Meeting Notes/Agendas, November, 1978-February, 1979 (Box 120, Folder 14)
      - Staff Memos, November-December, 1978 (Box 120, Folder 15)
      - Budget/Expenses, June, 1978-January, 1979 (Box 120, Folder 16)
      - Schedule Matters and Invitations, November, 1978-January, 1979 (Box 120, Folder 17)
      - Governor's Office: Organizational outline (annotated), undated (Box 120, Folder 18)
    - Study Team Organization
      - Study Team Name Lists and Job Descriptions, November, 1978-February, 1979 (Box 120, Folder 19)
      - Agriculture, November, 1978-February, 1979 (Box 120, Folder 20)
      - Commerce/Banking/Insurance/Securities Commission, August, 1978-January, 1979 (Box 120, Folder 21)
      - Energy/Environment, November, 1978-December, 1978 (Box 120, Folder 22)
      - Labor and Industry, October, 1977-January, 1979 (Box 120, Folder 23)
      - Personnel, May-December, 1978 (Box 120, Folder 24)
      - Personnel: Letters and Memos regarding labor and public employee issues, December, 1978 (Box 120, Folder 25)
      - Community Affairs: Historical and Museum, Arts, PPTN, November, 1978 (Box 120, Folder 26)
      - Health, Welfare and Drug Abuse and Aging, March-December, 1978 (Box 120, Folder 27)
      - Education: PHEAA, PHEFA, School Building Authority, State Tax Equal, November-December, 1978 (Box 120, Folder 28)
      - Transportation: Highways and Bridges and PA Turnpike, December, 1978 (Box 120, Folder 29)
      - Justice: State Police, Civil Defense, Military Affairs, Probation and Parole, H.R.C., Judicial Branch, November 13, 1978 (Box 120, Folder 30)
      - Finance & Budget, 1978 (Box 121, Folder 1)
      - Revenue and Budget Transition Memos, November-December, 1978 (Box 121, Folder 2)
      - Revenue and Budget Memo regarding Deficiency in Governor's Office Appropriation, December 27, 1978 (Box 121, Folder 3)
      - PA Commission for Women, November 21, 1978 (Box 121, Folder 4)
      - Rick A. Stafford (RAS) Notes, 1977-1978 (Box 121, Folder 5)
      - Rick A. Stafford (RAS) Daily Log, November 11, 1978 (Box 121, Folder 6)
      - Daily Staff Log (phone log), November-December, 1978 (Box 121, Folder 7)
      - Phone Logs, November 9, 1978 (Box 121, Folder 8)
      - Thornburgh's phone call notations (annotations), November-December 1978 (Box 121, Folder 9)
      - Governor's Review of Government Management, Inc., February-August, 1975 (Box 121, Folder 10)
      - PA Public Television Proposal: "Transition: A Governor Takes Office", September, 1978-February, 1979 (Box 121, Folder 11)
      - Rick A. Stafford (RAS) Plans and Notes, November, 1978-January, 1979 (Box 121, Folder 12)
      - Letters, Memos, Articles (annotated), November, 1978-December, 1979 (Box 121, Folder 13)
      - Correspondence to Thornburgh Governor Elect re study teams, November-December, 1978 (Box 121, Folder 14)
      - Shapp Letters regarding Judicial Appointment (including Governor Elect's response), December, 1978-January, 1979 (Box 121, Folder 15)
      - Former Governor Leader Administration Transition Reports and news releases, 1955-1958 (Box 121, Folder 16)
      - Clips from AP and UPI, December, 1978-January, 1979 (Box 121, Folder 17)
      - Clips - Editorials, December, 1978-January, 1979 (Box 121, Folder 18)
      - Clips- By Newspaper or Region, December, 1978-January, 1979 (Box 121, Folder 19)
      - Employee "Package" for Governor, undated (Box 121, Folder 20)
      - Memo regarding Public School Employer Retirement System, December 19, 1978 (Box 121, Folder 21)
      - Federal Funding Report of Region III Federal Regional Council, November 18, 1978 (Box 121, Folder 22)
      - Transition Briefing Paper on Pennsylvania by Mid-Atlantic Federal Regional Council, January, 1979 (Box 121, Folder 23)
    - Study Team Reports
      - Agriculture, October-December, 1978 (Box 122, Folder 1)
      - Budget, November 28, 1978-December 22, 1978 (Box 122, Folder 2)
      - Commerce & Business (annotated), December, 1978 (Box 122, Folder 3)
      - Community Affairs (annotated), December 21, 1978 (Box 122, Folder 4)
      - Education, March, 1976-November, 1978 (Box 122, Folder 5)
      - Education, October, 1977-December, 1978 (Box 122, Folder 6)
      - Environment: Transition Draft Report-revision, December 28, 1978 (Box 122, Folder 7)
      - Environment: Goals and Report to Transition Team, December, 1978 (Box 122, Folder 8)
      - Environment-DER (Department of Environmental Resources) (annotated), December 13-18, 1978 (Box 122, Folder 9-10)
      - Justice, December 20, 1978 (Box 122, Folder 11)
      - Labor and Industry (annotated), December, 1978 (Box 122, Folder 12-13)
      - Personnel (annotated), December 8, 1978 (Box 123, Folder 1)
      - Transportation (annotated), December 15, 1978 (Box 123, Folder 2)
      - Welfare & Health (annotated), August-December, 1978 (Box 123, Folder 3-4)
    - Cabinet Nominations
      - Cabinet Recommendations, October-December, 1978 (Box 123, Folder 5-7)
      - Cabinet Nominations, November 4, 1978-January 5, 1979 (Box 123, Folder 8)
      - Cabinet appointments: clippings, January 1979 (Box 123, Folder 9)
      - Robert Wilburn: Speech to Indiana County Chamber of Commerce, November 8, 1978 (Box 123, Folder 10)
    - Inaugural
      - Correspondence and memos, December, 1978 (Box 123, Folder 11)
      - Press arrangements, advisories schedules and news release, December, 1978-January, 1979 (Box 123, Folder 12)
      - Inauguration Oath of Office memo, December 13, 1978 (Box 123, Folder 13)
      - Inaugural Committee Press Kit, January, 1979 (Box 123, Folder 14)
      - Inaugural Day schedules, events, speech, January 16, 1979 (Box 123, Folder 15)
      - Clippings, January 17-18, 1979 (Box 123, Folder 16)
      - Inaugural headlines and activities compiled by Ann Thornburgh, January, 1979 (Box 123, Folder 17)
      - Inaugural related ephemera and invitations, January, 1979 (Box 123, Folder 18)
      - Ginny Thornburgh's Inaugural File, January, 1979 (Box 123, Folder 19)
      - Post Inaugural Scheduling, November, 1978-January, 1979 (Box 123, Folder 20)
      - Inaugural Book: "Inauguration Day 1979", January, 1979 (Box 123, Folder 21)